<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ACM on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/tags/acm/</link><description>Recent content in ACM on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 22:07:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/tags/acm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy ACM Submariner for connect overlay networks ARO - ROSA clusters</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/submariner/aro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 22:07:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/submariner/aro/</guid><description>Submariner is an open source tool that can be used with Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes to provide direct networking between pods and compatible multicluster service discovery across two or more Kubernetes clusters in your environment, either on-premises or in the cloud.
This article describes how to deploy ACM Submariner for connecting overlay networks of ARO and ROSA clusters.
NOTE: Submariner for connecting ARO and ROSA clusters only works from ACM 2.</description></item><item><title>Deploy ACM Submariner for connect overlay networks of ROSA clusters</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/submariner/rosa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 22:07:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/submariner/rosa/</guid><description>Submariner is an open source tool that can be used with Red Hat Advanced Cluster Management for Kubernetes to provide direct networking between pods and compatible multicluster service discovery across two or more Kubernetes clusters in your environment, either on-premises or in the cloud.
This article describes how to deploy ACM Submariner for connecting ROSA clusters overlay networks.
NOTE: ACM Submariner for ROSA clusters only works with ACM 2.7 or newer!</description></item><item><title>Advanced Cluster Management Observability on ROSA</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/observability/rosa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/observability/rosa/</guid><description>This document will take you through deploying ACM Observability on a ROSA cluster. see here for the original documentation.
Prerequisites An existing ROSA cluster An Advanced Cluster Management (ACM) deployment Set up environment Set environment variables
export CLUSTER_NAME=my-cluster export S3_BUCKET=$CLUSTER_NAME-acm-observability export REGION=us-east-2 export NAMESPACE=open-cluster-management-observability export SA=tbd export SCRATCH_DIR=/tmp/scratch export AWS_ACCOUNT_ID=$(aws sts get-caller-identity --query Account --output text) export AWS_PAGER=&amp;#34;&amp;#34; rm -rf $SCRATCH_DIR mkdir -p $SCRATCH_DIR Prepare AWS Account Create an S3 bucket</description></item></channel></rss>