<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Private Link on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/tags/private-link/</link><description>Recent content in Private Link on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/tags/private-link/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding a Public Ingress endpoint to a ROSA Private-Link Cluster</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/private-link/public-ingress/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/private-link/public-ingress/</guid><description>This is an example guide for creating a public ingress endpoint for a ROSA Private-Link cluster. Be aware of the security implications of creating a public subnet in your ROSA VPC this way.
Refer to the blog &amp;amp;ldquo;How to add public Ingress to a PrivateLink ROSA cluster&amp;amp;rdquo; , to expose applications to the internet by deploying in a PrivateLink Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS (ROSA) cluster within a truly private Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) that doesn’t have an internet gateway attached to it.</description></item><item><title>Creating a ROSA cluster with Private Link enabled (custom VPC) and STS</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/sts-with-private-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/sts-with-private-link/</guid><description>This is a combination of the private-link and sts setup documents to show the full picture
Prerequisites AWS CLI Rosa CLI v1.1.7 jq AWS Preparation If this is a brand new AWS account that has never had a AWS Load Balancer installed in it, you should run the following
aws iam create-service-linked-role --aws-service-name \ &amp;#34;elasticloadbalancing.amazonaws.com&amp;#34; Create the AWS Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) and Subnets For this scenario, we will be using a newly created VPC with both public and private subnets.</description></item><item><title>Creating a ROSA cluster with Private Link enabled</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/private-link/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/private-link/</guid><description>Prerequisites AWS CLI Rosa CLI v1.0.8 jq Create VPC and Subnets The following instructions use the AWS CLI to create the necessary networking to deploy a Private Link ROSA cluster into a Single AZ and are intended to be a guide. Ideally you would use an Automation tool like Ansible or Terraform to manage your VPCs.
When creating subnets, make sure that subnet(s) are created to an availability zone that has ROSA instances types available.</description></item></channel></rss>