<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OSD on Google Cloud on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in OSD on Google Cloud on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a OSD in GCP with Existing VPCs</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/osd_preexisting_vpc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/osd_preexisting_vpc/</guid><description>Tip The official documentation for installing a OSD cluster in GCP can be found here .
For deploy an OSD cluster in GCP using existing Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) you need to implement some prerequisites that you must create before starting the OpenShift Dedicated installation though the OCM.
Prerequisites gcloud CLI jq NOTE: Also the GCloud Shell can be used, and have the gcloud cli among other tools preinstalled.</description></item><item><title>Create Filestore Storage for OSD in GCP</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/filestore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/filestore/</guid><description>By default, within OSD in GCP only the GCE-PD StorageClass is available in the cluster. With this StorageClass, only ReadWriteOnce mode is permitted, and the gcePersistentDisks can only be mounted by a single consumer in read-write mode .
Because of that, and for provide Storage with Shared Access (RWX) Access Mode to our OpenShift clusters a GCP Filestore could be used.
GCP Filestore is not managed neither supported by Red Hat or Red Hat SRE team.</description></item></channel></rss>