<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuring IDP for ROSA, OSD and ARO on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/</link><description>Recent content in Configuring IDP for ROSA, OSD and ARO on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure Red Hat SSO with Azure AD as a Federated Identity Provider</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread-red-hat-sso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread-red-hat-sso/</guid><description>This guide demonstrates how to install and configure Red Hat SSO (Keycloak) into an Azure Red Hat OpenShift (ARO) cluster. It will also also configure the ARO cluster to use the SSO server as a mechanism to login by way of the OIDC protocol. In addition, Red Hat SSO can federate user identities with other identity providers. We will use Azure AD as an additional identity provider to show how this could be done.</description></item><item><title>What to consider when using Azure AD as IDP?</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/considerations-aad-ipd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 18:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/considerations-aad-ipd/</guid><description>Author: Ricardo Macedo Martins May 24, 2023
In this guide, we will discuss key considerations when using Azure Active Directory (AAD) as the Identity Provider (IDP) for your ARO or ROSA cluster. Below are some helpful references:
Configure ARO to Use Azure AD Configuring IDP for ROSA, OSD, and ARO Default Access for All Users in Azure Active Directory Once you set up AAD as the IDP for your cluster, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that by default, all users in your Azure Active Directory instance will have access to the cluster.</description></item><item><title>Configure Azure AD as an OIDC identity provider for ARO with cli</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread-aro-cli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread-aro-cli/</guid><description>The steps to add Azure AD as an identity provider for Azure Red Hat OpenShift (ARO) via cli are:
Prerequisites Have Azure cli installed Login to Azure Azure Define needed variables Get oauthCallbackURL Create &amp;lt;code&amp;gt;manifest.json&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt; file to configure the Azure Active Directory application Register/create app Add Service Principal for the new app Make Service Principal an Enterprise Application Create the client secret Update the Azure AD application scope permissions Get Tenant ID OpenShift Login to OpenShift as kubeadmin Create an OpenShift secret### Apply OpenShift OpenID authentication Wait for authentication operator to roll out Verify login through Azure Active Directory Last steps Prerequisites Have Azure cli installed Follow the Microsoft instuctions: https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Configure ARO to use Azure AD</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread-aro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread-aro/</guid><description>This guide demonstrates how to configure Azure AD as the cluster identity provider in Azure Red Hat OpenShift. This guide will walk through the creation of an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) application and configure Azure Red Hat OpenShift (ARO) to authenticate using Azure AD.
This guide will walk through the following steps:
Register a new application in Azure AD for authentication. Configure the application registration in Azure AD to include optional claims in tokens.</description></item><item><title>Configure Azure AD as an OIDC identity provider for ROSA/OSD</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/azuread/</guid><description>This guide demonstrates how to configure Azure AD as the cluster identity provider in Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS (ROSA). This guide will walk through the creation of an Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) application and configure Red Hat OpenShift Service on AWS (ROSA) to authenticate using Azure AD.
This guide will walk through the following steps:
Register a new application in Azure AD for authentication. Configure the application registration in Azure AD to include optional and group claims in tokens.</description></item><item><title>MOBB Docs and Guides - group-claims</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/group-claims/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/group-claims/</guid><description>MOBB Docs and Guides for group-claims</description></item><item><title>Using Group Sync Operator with Okta and ROSA/OSD</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/okta-grp-sync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/okta-grp-sync/</guid><description>Thatcher Hubbard
15 July 2022
This guide focuses on how to synchronize Identity Provider (IDP) groups and users after configuring authentication in OpenShift Cluster Manager (OCM).
To set up group synchronization from Okta to ROSA/OSD you must:
Define groups and assign users in Okta Install the Group Sync Operator from the OpenShift Operator Hub Create and configure a new Group Sync instance Set a synchronization schedule Test the synchronization process Define groups and assign users in Okta To synchronize groups and users with ROSA/OSD they must exist in Okta</description></item><item><title>Configure GitLab as an identity provider for ARO</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/gitlab-aro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/gitlab-aro/</guid><description>The following instructions will detail how to configure GitLab as the identity provider for Azure Red Hat OpenShift:
Register a new application in GitLab Create OAuth callback URL in ARO Log in and confirm Add administrative users or groups Register a new application in GitLab Log into GitLab and execute the following steps:
Go to Preferences
Select Applications from the left navigation bar
Provide a Name and enter an OAuth Callback URL as the Redirect URI in GitLab</description></item><item><title>Configure GitLab as an identity provider for ROSA/OSD</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/gitlab/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/gitlab/</guid><description>The following instructions will detail how to configure GitLab as the identity provider for Managed OpenShift through the OpenShift Cluster Manager (OCM):
Create OAuth callback URL in OCM Register a new application in GitLab Configure the identity provider credentials and URL Add cluster-admin or dedicated-admin users Log in and confirm Create OAuth callback URL in OCM Log in to the OpenShift Cluster Manager (OCM) to add a GitLab identity provider</description></item><item><title>Using Group Sync Operator with Azure Active Directory and ROSA</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/az-ad-grp-sync/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/az-ad-grp-sync/</guid><description>This guide focuses on how to synchronize Identity Provider (IDP) groups and users after configuring authentication in OpenShift Cluster Manager (OCM). For an IDP configuration example, please reference the Configure Azure AD as an OIDC identity provider for ROSA/OSD guide.
To set up group synchronization from Azure Active Directory (AD) to ROSA/OSD you must:
Define groups and assign users in Azure AD Add the required API permissions to the app registration in Azure AD Install the Group Sync Operator from the OpenShift Operator Hub Create and configure a new Group Sync instance Set a synchronization schedule Test the synchronization process Define groups and assign users in Azure AD To synchronize groups and users with ROSA/OSD they must exist in Azure AD</description></item></channel></rss>