<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other Red Hat Products on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/</link><description>Recent content in Other Red Hat Products on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Cluster Management</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/acm/</guid><description>Observability ROSA Submariner ROSA Submariner ARO Submariner</description></item><item><title>Migrate Kubernetes Applications with Konveyer Crane</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/crane/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/crane/</guid><description>Introduction Occasionally when you&amp;rsquo;re moving between major version of Kubernetes or Red Hat OpenShift, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to migrate your applications between clusters. Or if you&amp;rsquo;re moving between two clouds, you&amp;rsquo;ll want an easy way to migrate your workloads from one platform to another.
The Crane operator from the open source Konveyer project automates this migration process for you. The Konveyer site offers a selection of helpful projects to administer your cluster.</description></item><item><title>Deploying 3scale API Management to ROSA and OSD</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/3scale/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/3scale/</guid><description>This document will take you through deploying 3scale in any OSD or ROSA cluster. Review the official documentation here for more information or how to further customize or use 3scale.
Prerequisites An existing ROSA or OSD cluster Access to an AWS account with permissions to create S3 buckets, IAM users, and IAM policies A subscription for 3scale API Management A wildcard domain configured with a CNAME to your cluster&amp;rsquo;s ingress controller Prepare AWS Account Set environment variables (ensuring you update the variables appropriately!</description></item><item><title>Demonstrate GitOps on Managed OpenShift with ArgoCD</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/gitops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/gitops/</guid><description>Author: Steve Mirman Video Walkthrough If you prefer a more visual medium, you can watch Steve Mirman walk through this quickstart on YouTube .
The purpose of this document is to help you get OpenShift GitOps running in your cluster, including deploying a sample application and demonstrating how ArgoCD ensures environment consistency.
This demo assumes you have a Managed OpenShift Cluster available and cluster-admin rights.
GitHub resources referenced in the demo: BGD Application: gitops-bgd-app OpenShift / ArgoCD configuration: gitops-demo Required command line (CLI) tools GitHub: git OpenShift: oc ArgoCD: argocd Kustomize: kam Environment Set Up Install the OpenShift GitOps operator Install the OpenShift GitOps operator from the Operator Hub</description></item><item><title>Deploying Red Hat Advanced Cluster Security in ARO/ROSA</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/rhacs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/rhacs/</guid><description>This document is based in the RHACS workshop and in the RHACS official documentation .
Prerequisites An ARO cluster or a ROSA cluster . Set up the OpenShift CLI (oc) Download the OS specific OpenShift CLI from Red Hat Unzip the downloaded file on your local machine
Place the extracted oc executable in your OS path or local directory
Login to ARO / ROSA Login to your ARO / ROSA clusters with user with cluster-admin privileges.</description></item></channel></rss>