<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GPU on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/tags/gpu/</link><description>Recent content in GPU on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/tags/gpu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ROSA with Nvidia GPU Workloads</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/gpu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/gpu/</guid><description>ROSA guide to running Nvidia GPU workloads.
Prerequisites ROSA Cluster (4.10+) rosa cli #logged-in oc cli #logged-in-cluster-admin jq If you need to install a ROSA cluster, please read our ROSA Quickstart Guide . Please be sure you are installing or using an existing ROSA cluster that it is 4.10.x or higher.
As of OpenShift 4.10, it is no longer necessary to set up entitlements to use the nVidia Operator. This has greatly simplified the setup of the cluster for GPU workloads.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy Jupyter Notebook</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/jup/buildnotebook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/jup/buildnotebook/</guid><description>Retrieve the login command If you are not logged in via the CLI, access your cluster via the web console, then click on the dropdown arrow next to your name in the top-right and select Copy Login Command.
A new tab will open and select the authentication method you are using (in our case it&amp;rsquo;s github)
Click Display Token
Copy the command under where it says &amp;ldquo;Log in with this token&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Installing the Open Data Hub Operator</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/jup/opendatahub-gpu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/jup/opendatahub-gpu/</guid><description>The Open Data Hub operator is available for deployment in the OpenShift OperatorHub as a Community Operators. You can install it from the OpenShift web console:
From the OpenShift web console, log in as a user with cluster-admin privileges. For a developer installation from try.openshift.com including AWS and CRC, the kubeadmin user will work.
Create a new project named ‘jph-demo’ for your installation of Open Data Hub Find Open Data Hub in the OperatorHub catalog.</description></item><item><title>Jupyter Notebooks</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/jup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/jup/</guid><description>You will need the following prerequistes in order to run a basic Jupyter notebook with GPU on OpenShift
1. A OpenShift Cluster This will assume you have already provisioned a OpenShift cluster succesfully and are able to use it.
You will need to log in as cluster admin to deploy GPU Operator .
2. OpenShift Command Line Interface Please see the OpenShift Command Line section for more information on installing.</description></item><item><title>ARO with Nvidia GPU Workloads</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/aro/gpu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/aro/gpu/</guid><description>ARO guide to running Nvidia GPU workloads.
Prerequisites oc cli jq, moreutils, and gettext package ARO 4.10 If you need to install an ARO cluster, please read our ARO Quick start guide . Please be sure if you&amp;rsquo;re installing or using an existing ARO cluster that it is 4.10.x or higher.
As of OpenShift 4.10, it is no longer necessary to set up entitlements to use the nVidia Operator. This has greatly simplified the setup of the cluster for GPU workloads.</description></item></channel></rss>