<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installing the Kubernetes Secret Store CSI on OpenShift on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/secrets-store-csi/</link><description>Recent content in Installing the Kubernetes Secret Store CSI on OpenShift on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/secrets-store-csi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing the HashiCorp Vault Secret CSI Driver</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/secrets-store-csi/hashicorp-vault/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/secrets-store-csi/hashicorp-vault/</guid><description>The HashiCorp Vault Secret CSI Driver allows you to access secrets stored in HashiCorp Vault as Kubernetes Volumes.
Prerequisites An OpenShift Cluster (ROSA, ARO, OSD, and OCP 4.x all work) kubectl helm v3 Installing the Kubernetes Secret Store CSI Create an OpenShift Project to deploy the CSI into
oc new-project k8s-secrets-store-csi Set SecurityContextConstraints to allow the CSI driver to run (otherwise the DaemonSet will not be able to create Pods)</description></item><item><title>Azure Key Vault CSI on Azure Red Hat OpenShift</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/secrets-store-csi/azure-key-vault/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/secrets-store-csi/azure-key-vault/</guid><description>This document is adapted from the Azure Key Vault CSI Walkthrough specifically to run with Azure Red Hat OpenShift (ARO).
Prerequisites An ARO cluster The AZ CLI (logged in) The OC CLI (logged in) Helm 3.x CLI Environment Variables Run this command to set some environment variables to use throughout
Note if you created the cluster from the instructions linked above these will re-use the same environment variables, or default them to openshift and eastus.</description></item></channel></rss>