<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation from the MOBB on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation from the MOBB on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Red Hat Openshift Service on AWS</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/</guid><description>OpenShift on AWS allows users to run OpenShift in the Amazon Web Services (AWS) cloud, using AWS resources such as compute, storage, and networking. With OpenShift on AWS, users can leverage the benefits of the AWS cloud while also taking advantage of the features and capabilities of OpenShift. OpenShift on AWS is designed to be easy to use and to provide a smooth experience for developers, enabling them to focus on building and deploying applications rather than worrying about infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Azure Red Hat OpenShift</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/aro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/aro/</guid><description>Azure Red Hat OpenShift is a fully managed, cloud-based service that allows users to quickly and easily deploy and manage containerized applications on the Azure platform. This product is a collaboration between Microsoft Azure and Red Hat, two industry leaders in cloud computing and open source software development. With Azure Red Hat OpenShift, users can leverage the benefits of Azure&amp;rsquo;s global infrastructure and scalability, as well as Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s expertise in containerization and open source technologies.</description></item><item><title>Miscellaneous</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/misc/</guid><description>Misc Topics: Common Managed OpenShift References/Tasks Cost Management for Cloud Services Azure DevOps with Managed OpenShift Custom TLS Ciphers Jupyter Notebook K8s Secret Store CSI OADP Sharing Common Images Stop Default Router from Serving Custom Domains</description></item><item><title>Observability</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/o11y/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/o11y/</guid><description> Deploy Grafana on OpenShift 4 OpenShift Logging Azure Log Analytics</description></item><item><title>Other Red Hat Products</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/redhat/</guid><description> 3Scale API Management on ROSA and OSD RHACS on ARO/ROSA GitOps w/ ArgoCD Migrate K8s Apps w/ Konveyer Crane</description></item><item><title>OSD on Google Cloud</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/gcp/</guid><description> Filestore Storage for OSD on GCP Creating OSD on GCP w/ Existing VPC</description></item><item><title>Configuring IDP for ROSA, OSD and ARO</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/idp/</guid><description>Red Hat OpenShift on AWS (ROSA) and OpenShift Dedicated (OSD) provide a simple way for the cluster administrator to configure one or more identity providers for their cluster[s] via the OpenShift Cluster Manager (OCM) , while Azure Red Hat OpenShift relies on the internal cluster authentication operator .
The identity providers available for use are:
GitHub GitLab Google LDAP OpenID HTPasswd Configuring Specific Identity Providers ARO GitLab Azure AD Azure AD with Group Claims Azure AD via CLI Azure AD with Red Hat SSO ROSA/OSD GitLab Azure AD Azure AD with Group Claims (ROSA Only) Configuring Group Synchronization Using Group Sync Operator with Azure Active Directory and ROSA/OSD Using Group Sync Operator with Okta and ROSA/OSD</description></item><item><title>ARO Quickstart</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/quickstart-aro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/quickstart-aro/</guid><description>A Quickstart guide to deploying an Azure Red Hat OpenShift cluster.
Video Walkthrough If you prefer a more visual medium, you can watch Paul Czarkowski walk through this quickstart on YouTube .
Prerequisites Azure CLI Obviously you&amp;rsquo;ll need to have an Azure account to configure the CLI against.
MacOS
See Azure Docs for alternative install options.
Install Azure CLI using homebrew
brew update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; brew install azure-cli Linux
See Azure Docs for alternative install options.</description></item><item><title>ROSA Quickstart</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/quickstart-rosa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/quickstart-rosa/</guid><description>A Quickstart guide to deploying a Red Hat OpenShift cluster on AWS.
Video Walkthrough Quick Introduction to ROSA by Charlotte Fung on AWS YouTube channel If you prefer a more visual medium, you can watch Steve Mirman walk through this quickstart on YouTube .
Prerequisites AWS an AWS account with the AWS ROSA Prerequisites met.
MacOS
See AWS Docs for alternative install options.
Install AWS CLI using the macOS command line</description></item></channel></rss>