<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Examples of using a WAF in front of ROSA / OSD on AWS / OCP on AWS on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/</link><description>Recent content in Examples of using a WAF in front of ROSA / OSD on AWS / OCP on AWS on Managed OpenShift Black Belt - Unofficial Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS ALB</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/alb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/alb/</guid><description>Note: It is recommended that you use the Cloud Front based guide unless you absolutely must use an ALB based solution.
Here &amp;rsquo;s a good overview of AWS LB types and what they support
Problem Statement Operator requires WAF (Web Application Firewall) in front of their workloads running on OpenShift (ROSA)
Operator does not want WAF running on OpenShift to ensure that OCP resources do not experience Denial of Service through handling the WAF</description></item><item><title>This is a POC of ROSA with a AWS WAF service</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/readme-complex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/readme-complex/</guid><description>This is a POC of ROSA with a AWS WAF service Non working (yet) instructions for using STS to manage the creds for ALB
See https://issues.redhat.com/browse/CTONET-858 for a similar request
Here &amp;rsquo;s a good overview of AWS LB types and what they support
Problem Statement Customer requires WAF (Web Application Firewall) in front of their workloads running on OpenShift (ROSA)
Customer does not want WAF running on OpenShift to ensure that OCP resources do not experience Denial of Service through handling the WAF</description></item><item><title>Using CloudFront + WAF</title><link>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/cloud-front/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mobb.ninja/docs/rosa/waf/cloud-front/</guid><description>Problem Statement Operator requires WAF (Web Application Firewall) in front of their workloads running on OpenShift (ROSA)
Operator does not want WAF running on OpenShift to ensure that OCP resources do not experience Denial of Service through handling the WAF
Proposed Solution Add a CustomDomain resource to the cluster using a wildcard DNS and TLS certificate.
Set the Wildcard DNS CNAME&amp;rsquo;s to CloudFront and enable the CloudFront + WAF services to reverse proxy and inspect the traffic before sending it to the cluster.</description></item></channel></rss>